[AWAKEN]
[Episode 5]
Cheers to
the Greater East Asia Co-Prosperity!
-Cheers!
I am Hoshino Eisei.
Nice to meet you.
Chen Kailai,
you've risen to fame!
See for yourself.
[Weekly Supplement, Issue No. 238]
You managed to find such tiny print.
How very annoying.
I don't like this photo.
But I like the money.
It upsets you, though.
When people see this picture,
will they think of me as a traitor?
As long as you're not one,
why care about what others think?
Well...
Did they pay you?
No, not yet.
You should've asked for it.
With so many people there,
how could I have asked?
Maybe next time.
Fine.
You took the photos already.
Try not to be harsh on yourself.
Don't forget to get your pay.
If Li Musheng knew
that I promoted this kind of event,
he'd be very disappointed, wouldn't he?
Didn't Li Musheng often
take photos for traitors too?
But at critical times,
he chose to die for his beliefs.
If Li Musheng were still alive,
he would've been supportive
of you taking this job.
Only when you are strong enough
will you be able to do more.
When you put it that way,
taking photos for those people
is not necessarily a bad thing.
Of course.
Money is never a bad thing.
Perhaps this job
will be of help in the future.
What are you muttering about now?
I said,
I must get my pay back.
Newspapers! Newspapers for sale!
Co-prosperity! Co-prosperity!
Newspapers for sale!
Newspapers! Co-prosperity!
Read the newspaper!
Newspapers for sale!
Co-prosperity is on the way!
Co-prosperity!
Newspapers for sale!
The plague outbreaks in multiple places
are related to the Japanese's intention
of expanding the scope
of biological warfare
with Project Slumber.
I guess
they're trying to end the war quickly.
Right now,
we still haven't
found a way to decode Project Slumber.
We might gain an opportunity
through Hoshino.
[Delegation of the Japan Far East
Corporation arrives in Shanghai]
[to promote
the Greater Asia Co-Prosperity]
Shanghai Race Club.
♪ Clear waters stir in the cool breeze ♪
[Spring Meeting of Shanghai Race Club:
China-Japan Friendship Match]
Send one more team of guards
to the entrance.
Make sure no sharp weapons are brought in.
Got it.
Captain Cang, which horse is your pick?
The odds are so low
that they make me drowsy.
You're betting on a race like this?
Just for fun.
[China-Japan Friendship Match]
What a so-called
China-Japan friendship match.
How many of the audience are actually here
to watch the race?
Most of them are Japanese
who plan to put on a show.
And that woman, look.
She's even going to ride around the track
as the Chinese representative.
She takes all the spotlight,
while we have to do all the hard work.
What a massive crowd.
You're in for a challenging task,
Captain Cang.
No entry.
Cigarettes for sale!
Cigarettes, sunflower seeds,
and osmanthus candy for sale!
-How's your business today?
-Sir.
Not bad, I'd say.
I'll take a pack.
Everyone, get ready!
Load up!
Aim at the bullseye!
Fire!
This is my horse,
named Shenjun.
Shenjun?
How beautiful.
Cute, isn't it?
So handsome.
Handsome, yes.
Here's a gift for you.
I named this photo
"A Man."
Thank you.
You gave it a nice name.
"A Man."
I hope the war ends soon.
You also hate war?
Who would love it?
My name is Chen Kailai.
I'm a Chinese photographer.
My name is Shota Ishida.
I'm Dr. Hoshino's assistant.
Pleased to meet you.
Pleased to meet you too.
Watch out!
Su Men!
Why just stand there?
Protect Mr. Hoshino!
Quick, run!
Surround them, now!
The sniper's on the rooftop
across the track. Hurry!
Across the track!
Get a move on!
Escort Mr. Hoshino out of here.
Careful.
Move faster!
Hurry!
Come with me!
Watch your back!
Ms. Su Men...
Go away!
I'm fine. Quick, run!
Move!
Move now!
Let's go!
Hurry, guys! Keep up!
Go!
Quick!
Chen Kailai?
It's never easy to earn your money.
That's the guy!
Go after him!
Hurry! Go after him!
Quick!
Run faster!
I failed.
Help these people! Quick!
Go inside!
Doctor, quick!
-Go inside!
-Get in there!
-Keep going in.
-This way!
Make way please!
Don't crowd up here. Come on.
This way.
This way, please.
Go! This way!
A spring-loaded gun of this sort
is pretty compact.
It was used only to create
a distraction...
General,
we have found out
the mastermind behind this incident.
The steel balls are coated with poison,
which is exactly usually used
by the Hurricane Team.
The antidote has been sent
to Renji Hospital.
Inspector Su only suffered
superficial wounds.
She is fine.
Director Li,
I've long admired your talent.
I hope you won't disappoint me again!
I know, General,
that you are highly concerned about
the insurgents lurking in Shanghai.
Please give me a month.
I promise to root out
the spy network of the NBIS.
I hope you will succeed this time.
If not,
I will resign immediately.
There should be punishment for failures.
I got it.
I will accept punishment
if I fail.
That's too intense, Director Li.
You're a pillar of the state.
But now, things are complicated
in Shanghai.
That's why I assigned Su Men
to be your assistant.
As it turns out,
I made the right choice.
Inspector Su's performance
in this incident truly shows
what a heroine she is.
You are a pillar of the state,
while she is a heroine.
You should hold each other in high regard.
Whatever grudges between the two of you,
Director Li, I hope you will
always prioritize the big picture.
General,
you are mistaken.
There are no grudges
between Inspector Su and me.
Once she recovers,
No. 76 welcomes her back anytime.
How is Chen Kailai doing?
The doctors said they'd try their best.
Get him the finest doctor.
I want him to live.
Got it.
Inspector Su, may I come in?
Sure.
Dr. Hoshino insisted on visiting you.
Forgo the formalities.
Dr. Hoshino,
how's your injury?
Not serious at all.
I heard you were poisoned, Inspector Su.
Is it so?
This is the best antidote for me.
Every time I meet with you, Inspector Su,
there are always surprises.
Dr. Hoshino,
alcohol can be a pain reliever.
Care for a try?
Thank you for saving my life,
Inspector Su.
Be seated, please.
Sure.
The transfusion is almost finished.
The patient has lost too much blood.
Get him another bag.
We just received some wounded soldiers.
The blood bank is out of plasma.
I don't care.
Figure it out yourselves. Hurry!
But...
I have type O blood.
Available for testing and use anytime.
Will he live?
It's hard to tell.
We've given him the antidote,
but he has lost too much blood.
Make use of the time then.
It only counts if the patient lives.
The patient has come to!
I guess Chen Kailai is hiding
in the hospital,
with a bad case of laziness.
Where is Ward 1?
Right here.
You already woke up?
Chen Kailai, you're awake now?
Hand me the flowers.
Remember, you must live a long life.
My wound...
Put them in a vase.
You seem to be in great spirits.
Does it really hurt that much?
I brought your favorite food.
Miss, please be quiet.
The patient is not out of danger yet.
He can't eat now.
"Not out of danger yet"?
You look pretty fine to me.
Better listen to the doctor.
Just take a bite in secret.
The nurse won't notice.
Come on.
Eat up.
Is it good?
Are you hungry?
You eat it then, alright?
Why would he be hungry?
He has done nothing all day,
except for holding a bouquet.
I'm really not hungry,
because I can't feel it anymore.
You're full of anger then.
You got shot by a spring-loaded gun,
which is also known
as a ball-bearing gun.
It's a simple form of firearm,
as it just consists of a tiny steel tube.
But it could be lethal
when fired from a short range.
It's rather discreet.
This time, you got lucky.
How knowledgeable of you.
I read all that from the magazine,
The Detective, published by Youli Company.
My absolute favorite
is The Detective Stories of Huo Sang.
Even a person like me
loves literature.
I want to sleep.
Fine.
We'll visit you again in a few days then.
Oh, right.
Du Huangqiao is such a weird guy.
He told me to ask you if you are hungry.
What should I tell him?
Tell him yes.
What does he mean?
He must be wondering
if Kailai is making a fast recovery.
The hungrier you are,
the faster you'll recover.
This blind man is cleverer
than I thought.
I'm leaving then.
The flowers will stay here with you.
I'll take these wontons away.
Since you're not
eating them, I will.
Let's go now.
I had the General Affairs Division
prepare an office for you, Inspector Su.
I prefer the previous one.
That was for temporary use.
Inspector Su, you arrived in a haste.
This office is not exactly ready yet.
Actually, it seems rather fine to me.
All government departments
practice frugality now.
I deeply admire
No. 76's approach of setting
an example through its own actions.
You may keep both offices.
The Imperial Japanese Army Headquarters
provides a monthly operating budget
of 300,000.
We can certainly afford two offices.
As long as an expenditure is justifiable
and worthwhile,
we'll be fully supportive of it.
Inspector Su, your acts at the race club
are unforgettable.
Investigating corruption
is certainly important.
That said, recently,
the NBIS and the Communist Party
are intensifying their operations.
I've already talked
with the Nanjing government.
If you don't mind, Inspector Su,
please stay in Shanghai for now
to assist Director Li
in suppressing the subversive elements.
Sure.
Director Li,
from this very moment on,
should Inspector Su's safety
be compromised...
From today on, if anything happens
to Dr. Hoshino
and his team, or Inspector Su,
No. 76 will take full responsibility.
Oh, right.
The Hurricane Squad's actions
are getting rampant these days.
Director Li, I wonder
if you have any plans.
Their disorder must be checked at once.
I've devised a plan already.
Inspector Su, just focus on your recovery.
No need to worry about these matters.
Then I'll count on those elites
under you, Director Li.
The number of No. 76 agents
lying in wait in the streets
is much larger than you could imagine,
Inspector Su.
Director Li has made me a promise.
That is, within one month,
he will eradicate the NBIS spy network
in Shanghai.
The Hurricane Squad is running wild.
They have to be eliminated
at once, or I'll be too embarrassed
to remain at my post as a director.
Are there any clues about that ace agent
of the NBIS,
named the God of Wealth?
There will be.
There will be clues about him soon.
An ace agent...
Director Li, you have
your own top enforcer too, right?
Then let's see whose ace agent
is more competent.
You're awake.
Leave the hospital.
Right now?
The doctor said I couldn't be discharged
until after a few more days.
You can't completely trust or ignore
what a doctor says.
From now on, you must
listen to your master.
I realized long ago
that you are feigning blindness.
You don't even put in much effort.
Cut the crap.
♪ I am Xi Shi ♪
♪ What a warm, sunny day it is ♪
♪ Let me go out to wash silk ♪
"Xi Shi Washing Silk," huh?
So you can sing Yue Opera, boss lady.
I've got a whole lot more.
Such a shame.
No one's playing
the three-stringed instrument today.
It's typical of that blind old man.
He's off and on with his work.
Still the usual, right?
Yes, the usual.
Prepare a special room for Mr. Zhao.
A Yangzhou-style pedicure, too.
Coming right up!
Mr. Zhao,
I'll be waiting inside.
Sure.
You seem a bit off today, boss lady.
How so?
You're more languid than usual—
looking even more charming.
Oh, you.
One male guest, to a special care room.
This way, please.
[Fairy Bath]
This stuff of mine works even better
than that in the hospital.
You have to believe someone
who survived the battlefield.
But it hurts a lot.
Such a slight pain amounts to nothing.
Pull yourself together.
You will face things that are way worse
than this in the future.
What do you mean?
Make sure you do your job well at No. 76.
My job is only to take photos
for Inspector Su.
I have a hunch
that you will be highly valued at No. 76.
Blind people can tell fortunes.
You are not really blind.
You have sharper eyes than anyone else.
Why do you care so much about
my personal affairs?
Are you with the Nationalists
or the Communists?
You know the answer, don't you?
You've never told me the truth.
How am I supposed to know?
One day, you will.
Secure the area. Quick!
Protect Mr. Hoshino!
Hurry!
♪ A true gentleman
never forgets a kindness ♪
This is "The Ten Beauties."
A true gentleman never forgets a kindness.
I didn't see you here yesterday.
Got a side gig at another store?
Mr. Zhao,
are you taking this place as a hotel?
The Fairy Bath is cozier than hotels.
I was just wondering
why you're a bit languid today.
You got injured?
A sprained ankle is no small issue.
You'll get well in a couple of days
with Dr. Jiang's
secret home formula for healing ointment.
He's rather concerned
about your sprained ankle.
What grateful workers you've employed,
boss lady.
You're fortunate.
Human relationships are reciprocal.
I'm taking off.
Sorry I can't see you out.
Take care, sir.
Goodbye.
It takes some time
for your injury to heal.
Better be cautious from now on.
Where is the shop owner?
I am the shop owner.
Section Chief Zhao.
Be careful not to catch a chill.
Thanks to you, my life was saved.
I haven't had a chance to thank you yet.
You were in great luck.
That's true.
We are lucky and blessed.
Just you watch,
we will be rich soon.
The photos in the display window
are well taken.
No wonder Inspector Su
would designate you
to be her photographer.
I also think these are well taken.
Careful, careful.
Here, come on.
Get in the bed.
Where's the booze?
I've never seen him drink that much.
Perhaps he's just thrilled
about your survival.
I'll take care of him.
You go home and get some rest.
It's been so many years.
If you have any questions, ask away.
No need to sneak around.
Everyone has their secrets.
I won.
Tell me your secrets first.
Did you not apply the medicine I gave you?
You bandaged it yourself?
At this rate, you'll get infected.
The NBIS only teaches how to kill,
but never self-rescue skills.
In their eyes, your life
isn't worth even a dime.
Don't be terrified!
Sir, I entertain through singing only,
not sexual services!
Let go of me!
Did you do this?
Work for me.
Will you?
Have you learned it?
From now on,
replace the dressing like this once a day.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I'm indebted to you after all.
If I had known you were this good,
I might not have helped you back then.
Who exactly are you?
Du Huangqiao, the former commander
of the 3rd Battalion, 5th Regiment,
145th Division.
What about now?
Now...
I'm here to protect you.
Alright.
Look here, everyone.
Lower your heads a bit and smile.
Little one, look here.
Good.
Take care.
Thank you.
Jinbao, I need to go out.
For what?
You watch the store.
Are you the boss here or am I?
You are!
Musheng,
you said you've never been to Shanghai.
If you ever come here one day,
I will surely show you around
this place where I grew up.
There are many vendors at the entrance
of the valley where I reside.
They sell dried radish and small wontons.
Rice soaked in broth, too.
My favorite street
is the Bubbling Well Road next to my home.
I bought a custom-made
water-green silk cheongsam here,
which is my favorite.
It only takes about ten minutes by tram
from my home to the Bund.
The sunset here is the most beautiful.
I hope one day we can
stand side by side on the bridge
and watch it together.
For cake, you must go to Kaisiling.
They sell a kind of cake
that was named after a French emperor,
the Napoleon.
With multiple layers
of puff pastry, it's filled with
fresh cream and custard.
This...
Can I have half a piece of it?
Put it on my tab.